knowledgehound.com 2017-12-09

# KnowledgeHound - Privac Policy

Effective Date: July 18, 2017

Vyzion Inc. dba KnowledgeHound is committed to protecting your Privacy. Please see below for an overview on how we handle your personal information and data.

##### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

KnowledgeHound participates in and has certified it’s compliance with the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks. KnowledgeHound is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. KnowledgeHound has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. <https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>.

The United States Federal Trade Commission (FTC) is the enforcement authority with jurisdiction over this compliance with the Privacy Shield.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, KnowledgeHound commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact KnowledgeHound at:

Privacy Officer  
Vyzion, Inc. dba KnowledgeHound  
220 North Green Street  
Chicago, IL 60607  
or  

KnowledgeHound has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit <http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacyshield/for-eu-consumers> for more information and to file a complaint. Where a complaint cannot be resolved by any of the before mentioned recourse mechanisms, individuals may have a right to invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel as a recourse mechanism of ‘last resort’.

##### What type of information do we collect?

###### For KnowledgeHound Customers

  * Personal Data. Such as name and work email address when registering to use our services.
  * Usage data. We collect usage data about you whenever you interact with our services. This may include what search terms you have entered, which webpages you are visiting on our site, what you click on, when you performed those actions, and so on. Additionally, like most websites today, our web servers keep log files that record data each time a device accesses those servers. The log files contain data about the nature of each access, including originating IP addresses, internet service providers, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system versions, and timestamps.
  * Your Research Data. We collect information captured from market research studies provided to us by you. Examples of this information can include survey data, documents, and video or audio files.
  * Other data you intentionally share. We may collect your personal information or data if you submit it to us in other contexts. For example, if you provide us with a testimonial or case study.

###### For Individuals who Participate in Research Conducted by our Customers

  * Personal Data. We collect information captured from market research studies provided to us by our customers. Personal data may exist from this research which could be stored and accessed by our customers in the format of a document or video file.
  * Survey Data. We collect Survey Data from market research studies provided to us by our customers. For your protection, it is KnowledgeHound’s policy to always ensure this data is anonymized before being accepted and stored on our platform.

##### How do we use the information we collect?

###### For KnowledgeHound customers

We use the information we collect from you for two purposes:

To provide you with our services

  * To enable you to search for, analyze, and visualize relevant data from your research.
  * To enable our Customer Success team to assist you. This requires us to access your information to assist you.

To manage our services

  * To facilitate account creation and the log in process.
  * To enforce our Terms of Use.
  * To contact you about your service or account. We occasionally send you communications of a transactional nature (e.g. service-related announcements, billing-related matters, changes to our services or policies, a welcome email when you first register). You can’t opt out of these communications since they are required to provide our services to you.
  * To monitor, maintain, and improve our services and features. We internally perform statistical and other analysis on your usage data to analyze and measure user behavior and trends, to understand how people use our services, and to monitor, troubleshoot and improve our services, including to help us evaluate or devise new features. We may use your information for internal purposes designed to keep our services secure and operational, such as for troubleshooting and testing purposes, and for service improvement, marketing, research and development purposes.
  * To contact you for marketing purposes. You may opt out of these communications at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link included in any communication.
  * To respond to legal requests and prevent harm. If we receive a subpoena or other legal request, we may need to inspect the data we hold to determine how to respond.

###### For individuals whose information was collected by our customers

  * Your Personal and Survey Data is owned and managed by our Customers, and we treat that information as private to the customer. Please contact any Customer directly to understand how they will use your information collected. Some Customers may provide you with a privacy policy or notice at the time you participate in their research and we encourage you to review that to understand how the Customer will handle your responses.

KnowledgeHound does not sell your information to any third parties and we will not use your information to contact you.

##### With whom do we share your information?

###### For customers and individuals who participate in research conducted by our customers, we may disclose:

  * Your information to our service providers: We use service providers who help us to provide our customers with our services. We give relevant persons working for some of these providers access to your information, but only to the extent necessary for them to perform their services for us. We also implement reasonable contractual and technical protections to ensure the confidentiality of your information and data is maintained, used only for the provision of their services to us, and handled in accordance with this privacy policy. Examples of service providers include hosting services, transcription or translation services, and data cleaning services. _Note that we may be liable for the appropriate transfer of EU and/or Swiss personal data to third parties_.
  * Aggregated or de-identified information to third parties to improve or promote our services. No individuals can reasonably be identified or linked to any part of the information we share with third parties to improve or promote our services.
  * Your information if required or permitted by law. We may disclose your information as required or permitted by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, subpoena, or other legal process served on us. Note that we may be required to release EU and/or Swiss individual’s personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities including to meet national security and/or law enforcement requirements.
  * Your information if there’s a change in business ownership or structure. If ownership of all or substantially all of our business changes, or we undertake a corporate reorganization (including a merger or consolidation), you expressly consent to KnowledgeHound transferring your information to the new owner or successor entity so that we can continue providing our services. If required, KnowledgeHound will notify the applicable data protection agency in each jurisdiction of such a transfer in accordance with the notification procedures under applicable data protection laws.

##### What are my rights to the information you collect?

###### For KnowledgeHound Customers

Your research data is owned by you. Not only that, but KnowledgeHound treats your research data as if it were private. We don’t sell this data to anyone and we don’t use your research data for purposes unrelated to you or our services, except in a limited set of circumstances (e.g. if we are compelled by a subpoena, or if you’ve given us permission to do so).

In addition to the above, you have the following rights:

  * Access and correct your Personal Data. KnowledgeHound acknowledges the right of EU and Swiss individuals to access their personal data. As a registered user, you may access and correct certain personal information that KnowledgeHound holds about you by contacting your Customer Success representative. Some users (including those whose information we receive under the EU-U.S. and Swiss-US Privacy Shield) have certain legal rights to obtain information of whether we hold personal information about them, to access personal information we hold about them, and to obtain its correction, update, amendment or deletion in appropriate circumstances. In all cases, requests to exercise these rights may be directed to our Privacy Officer (please see contact information towards the front of this policy). These rights are subject to some exceptions, such as where giving you access would have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other individuals. We will respond to your request to exercise these rights within a reasonable time and, where required by law or where we deem it otherwise appropriate and practicable to do so, we will honor your request.
  * Download/backup your research data. We provide you with the ability to export, share and publish your research data in a variety of formats. This allows you to create your own backups or conduct offline data analysis.
  * Delete and send back your research data. You may delete your research data for any particular research study at any given time from our system by contacting your Customer Service Representative. As long as you maintain an account with us, we may retain your deleted data for a limited time in case you requested to delete something by accident and need to restore it. In the event you should terminate your agreement with KnowledgeHound, we will permanently delete your data, to the extent permitted by law, from our systems. Upon deletion, we will provide all research data back to customer in it’s originally delivered format.

###### For Individuals who Participate in Research Conducted by our Customers

  * Contact the Customer to access and correct your Personal and Survey data. Because we collect research provided by our customers, you will need to contact the customer if you have any questions about the research conducted, or if you want to access, update, or delete anything related to your Personal data collected in the research. You may request access to and correction of the personal data we hold about you by contacting our Privacy Officer, but in most cases KnowledgeHound cannot provide you with this access since all data related to the research we collect is our customer’s private information and giving you access may have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other individuals. We will respond to your request for access or correction within a reasonable time and, where reasonable and practicable to do so, we will provide access to your personal data in the manner requested by you.

##### Security and other important information

###### For customers and individuals who participate in research conducted by our customers, we may disclose:

  * Security. KnowledgeHound is committed to protecting the security of your information. Security technologies and procedures are employed to help protect your information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. All personal data is stored on computer servers with limited access, located in secured facilities. When we transmit Personal Data over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. For customers, if a password is provided to help protect your research data and personal data, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential.
  * Data locations. Our servers are based in the United States, so your information will be hosted in the United States. We utilize data processors in the UK and India as well.
  * Choice. With the exception of sharing your information with our service providers whom we have contractually bound to act as an agent on our behalf, individuals have the opportunity to choose (opt out) whether their personal information is (i) to be disclosed to a third party or (ii) to be used for a purpose that is materially different from the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by the individuals. To exercise this choice, please contact our Privacy Officer.
  * Cookies. We and our partners use cookies and similar technologies on our websites. Cookies are small bits of data we store on the device you use to access our services so we can recognize repeat users. Each cookie expires after a certain period of time, depending on what we use it for. We use cookies and similar technologies for several reasons:
    * To make our site easier to use.
    * For security reasons. We use cookies to authenticate your identity, such as confirming whether you are currently logged into KnowledgeHound
    * To provide you with personalized content. We may store user preferences, such as your default language, in cookies to personalize the content you see.
    * To improve our services. We use cookies to measure your usage of our websites and track referral data, as well as to occasionally display different versions of content to you. This information helps us to develop and improve our services and optimize the content we display to users.
    * Google Analytics. In addition to the above, we have implemented on our websites and other services certain Google Analytics features to track and understand your behavior with the goal of improving our service.
